Finding Aid for the Leon Hoage Collection of Material about the Lindbergh Kidnapping Case LSC.1066
UCLA Library Special Collections
Leon Hoage collection of material about the Lindbergh Kidnapping Case
1932-1950
UCLA Library Special Collections
Hoage, Leon
LSC.1066
2.0 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
Leon Hoage was hired by New Jersey Governor Harold Hoffman to help investigate the 1932 kidnapping of the Charles A. Lindbergh, Jr. Collection consists of photographs, clippings, and Photostats of evidence used in Bruno Richard Hauptmann's trial, and correspondence between Hoffman and Hoage regarding the case.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Lyra Hoage, 1963.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942331533606533
Biography
Leon Hoage was hired by New Jersey Governor Harold Hoffman to help investigate the 1932 kidnapping of Charles Augustus Lindbergh, Jr. His examination of evidence and testimonies led him to claim that the Lindbergh kidnapping was an "inside job" and that Bruno Richard Hauptmann was innocent of the crime for which he was convicted and executed.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of photographs, clippings, and Photostats of evidence used in Bruno Richard Hauptmann's trial, typescript drafts of analyses, as well as correspondence between New Jersey Governor Harold Hoffman and crime analyst Hoage regarding the case.
Trials (Kidnapping) -- New Jersey -- Archives.; Hauptmann, Bruno Richard; Hoage, Leon--Archives.; Linbergh, Charles A. (Charles Augustus)
- Police investigation files, 1932. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Statements, reports including major initial report, telegrams, letters concerning evidence, notes from a meeting profiling the kidnapper (Photostats).
- Police investigation files, 1932-1934. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Investigations of Carl Oswin Giessler, Therese and Wilhelm Krippendorf, and Bruno Richard Hauptmann (Photostats). Includes information on Hauptmann's financial accounts, Hauptmann's fishing and hunting license, and a statement from Harry Eberhardt.
- Police investigation files, 1936. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Letters, reports and affidavits (primarily Photostats). Includes letters received from "JD" concerning Reverend Michael Kallok, letters regarding suggestion that Lindbergh ransom money appeared in Cuba, affidavits of Frederick and Anna Klein, and a claim that baby was seen in New Hampshire.
- Police investigation files, undated. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Reports, jury information (Photostats).
- Handwriting files, ca. 1932-1934. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Handwriting analysis reports (Photostats).
- Correspondence and investigation notes, 1935-1938. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Photostats, copies and typescript.
- Letters and case reports sent to Governor Hoffman, 1935-1936. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bruno Richard Hauptmann notes, ca. 1937. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Typed notes on Hauptmann's background, testimony related to investigation.
- Ransom notes, originals, 1932. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Some of the original ransom notes received by Charles Lindbergh.
- Ransom notes, Photostats, 1932. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Copies of ransom notes received by Charles Lindbergh from police files.
- Letters and notes, ca. 1936-1937. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Analysis regarding "faked" postcard ransom note (typescript).
- Paul Wendel statements, 1936. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Statements by Wendel Sr., Dr. Carroll Jones (typescript).
- Paul Wendel clippings, 1936-1937. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Press clippings.
- Hoffman investigation clippings, 1936-1937. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Clippings about Harold G. Hoffman's investigation into Hauptmann's case and aftermath, includes clippings about Bruno Richard Hauptmann and his wife Anna.
- Hoffman investigation clippings, 1935-1940. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Press clippings about Harold G. Hoffman's investigation into Hauptmann's case and aftermath.
- Amandus Hochmuth testimony and clippings, ca. 1938. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Clippings, testimony and draft letter to the editor from Hoage related to Amandus Hochmuth's testimony against Hauptmann.
- Hoage investigation clippings, 1938-1961. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Clippings. Includes maps and a plan of Hauptmann's attic.
- Correspondence with Hoffman, 1941-1950. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Letters exchanged between Leon Hoage and Harold Hoffman.
- Letters to Kerry Shaw, 1948. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Information sent to Kerry Shaw for an article, includes letter of rejection from Coronet Magazine.
- Drafts of letters, 1949-1950.; Typescript. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Articles and stories by Hoage, ca. 1941-1947.; Annotated typescript drafts. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Analysis by Hoage regarding handwriting and ladder, ca. 1939.; Typescript drafts. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Report to Hoffman on John Condon, 1936.; Typescript drafts. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Index of police files, 1937. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Alphabetical listings and descriptions of evidence and witnesses.
- Notes on testimony and evidence, ca. 1932-1937.; Typed notes. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Investigation photographs, 1932-1937. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Includes photograph of Charles Augustus Lindbergh, suspects, Hauptmann's attic, ladder found at crime site, cemetery where ransom drop occurred, shipyard where baby was said to be held, Lindbergh employees including Violet Sharpe, ransom notes, investigators and consultants.
- Hoage report to Mark Kimberling, undated.; Annotated typescript draft, 41 pages (folder 1 of 2). (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Hoage report to Mark Kimberling, undated.; Annotated typescript draft, 267 pages (folder 2 of 2). (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Notes for Hoage's analysis, ca. 1932-1940.; Annotated typed notes and press clippings. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Under the Lens of Truth: The Concealed Facts of the Lindbergh Case Laid Bare, analysis of Lindbergh case, undated.; Annotated typescript draft, 174 pages. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Brief Partial Analysis of the Lindbergh Case, Part I, undated.; Annotated typescript draft, 79 pages. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Copy of second installment "sent to Ken", 1938. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Analysis of Hauptmann attic and nails, typescript draft, 22 pages.
- What 50 Million Americans Failed to See, Part I: Analysis of Evidence existing March 1932, undated. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Notes and research material, two annotated typescript drafts.
- What 50 Million Americans Failed to See, Part II: The Hauptmann Angle, ca. 1944.; Two annotated typescript drafts. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Scapegoat, by Anthony Scaduto, 1976. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Book Scapegoat: the lonesome death of Bruno Richard Hauptmann by Anthony Scaduto. New York: Putnam, 1976